#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

# Nikola Furnadjiski



- +389 71 264 063
- nikola.furnadjiski@outlook.com
- Personal website https://nikola-furnadjiski.github.io/me/
- 1 LinkedIn profile https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikola-furnadjiski-28b637b0
- Location Skopje, Macedonia

## **POSITION**

# Software Engineer

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

"At the end it all comes down to one thing, how bad do you want it!"

#### ABOUT ME

Software engineer with 6+ years of professional working experience.

Worked with both front-end and back-end technologies with accent on the Angular framework in recent period.

Worked as a part of small projects (4-5 people) located at one physical location as well as a part of huge projects (100+ people) divided into multiple locations.

Experience with agile methodologies.

Passionate about learning new technologies and methodologies.

Experience with high school competitions with notable results in solving algorithmic problems.

#### JOB APPLIED FOR

Senior Angular Software Engineer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## 09/2021 - present

# Senior Angular Software Engineer

Employer: Valtech - Skopje, Macedonia

- Working for a FinTech startup company on a project based on Angular in the domain of crypto currencies and DeFi (decentralized finances)
- Team of 6 people from multiple physical locations
- Technologies used: HTML5 / CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Angular, Git, Scrum

#### 01/2021 - 08/2021

# Intermediate Angular Software Engineer

Employer: Endava – Skopje, Macedonia

- Did a career switch from back-end to front-end developer upon my request. After self-acquired the needed knowledge and did some practise projects, got evaluated by the company with a conclusion that I fulfil the criteria and got switched to an Angular front-end developer on the same project already working as a back-end developer
- Working on a huge project (120+ developers) for a client from USA from the marketing sector
- Technologies used: HTML5/CSS3, Javascript, Typescript, npm, Angular, Material Design

Curriculum Vitae Nikola Furnadjiski



## 11/2019 – 12/2020 Intermediate Java Software Engineer

Employer: Endava - Skopje, Macedonia

- Working on a huge project (120+ developers) for a client from USA from the marketing sector. Previously worked for a client from Netherland from the banking sector (30+ developers)
- Technologies used: Java, Spring/Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySql, OracleDB, MsSql, Postgres, Atlassian's Bitbucket/Jira/Conflience, IntelliJ...

# 07/2019 – 10/2019 Intermediate Java Software Engineer

Employer: Musala Soft - Skopje, Macedonia

 Working on different projects mainly with technologies: Java, Spring/Spring Boot, JQuery, Git, Gitlab, Trello, IBM Watson Assistant/Discovery, Mongo...

# 07/2018 – 07/2019 Junior Java Software Engineer

Employer: Musala Soft - Skopje, Macedonia

 Working on different projects mainly with technologies: Java, Spring/Spring Boot, Hibernate, Informix, Weblogic Server, Git, Gitlab, Trello

## 03/2016 – 07/2018 Junior Software Engineer

Employer: One Inside - Skopje, Macedonia

 Working on various projects with various technologies, both frontend and backend technologies, amongst them are: Java, AEM, NodeJS, HTML/CSS, JS, JQuery, Angular 1, Angular 2, Ionic, TypeScript...

## 09/2012 – 06/2013 Competitive programming tutor of Olympiad IT students from Yahya Kemal

Employer: High School Yahya Kemal - Skopje, Macedonia

 Working part-time while studying university as a mentor/tutor of high school students which competed in regional, national and Olympiad IT competitions in Macedonia. Solving algorithmic problems in C++ programming language.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# 09/2012 - 12/2016 University Ss. Cyril and Methodius in Skopje

Faculty of Computer Science and Engineering - FINKI

- Bachelor's degree with 4-year studies, 240 ECTS, GPA 9.13 / 10.00
- Field: Computer Science and Engineering

# 09/2008 - 06/2012 Yahya Kemal College - Skopje

High School in Skopje, education completely in English

- 4-year studies, GPA 5.00 / 5.00
- Field: Mathematics



## PERSONAL SKILLS

#### Mother tongue

#### Macedonian

## Other language(s)

**English** 

Turkish

German

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
A2	A2	A2	A2	A2
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2 Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

#### Communication skills

Good communication skills in English, gained through high school, which was completely in English, improved while working for abroad companies and abroad clients where communication between clients and abroad colleagues was also completely in English.

## Organisational / managerial skills

- Able to work under pressure
- Able to work in short deadlines
- Team player
- Able to listen and accept another idea
- Passionate about learning new technologies and methodologies

# Job-related skills

- Experience with Scrum agile method of development
- Experience with GIT version control system using command line, github, gitlab and bitbucket
- Experience with software package Jira/Confluence
- Experience with working in teams separated on difference physical locations, experience working and communicating directly with foreign clients

# Programming Languages and Frameworks

 Java SE7, Java SE8, Java SE11, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JavaScript, Typescript, Angular 2+, NodeJS, Ionic

#### **Databases**

Informix, MySql, MsSql, OracleDB, Postgres, MongoDb, FireBase.

# Other

 HTML/CSS, SASS, XML, UML, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Shell/Bash, Atlassian Jira/Confluence/Bitbucket, Slack, Microsoft Teams, GIT, Algorithms... Curriculum Vitae Nikola Furnadjiski



## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **Projects**

## Startup client from FinTech - Valtech

Working for a FinTech startup company on a project based on Angular 8 months

- In domain of crypto currencies and DeFi (decentralized finances)
- Team of 6 people from multiple physical locations
- Technology used: Angular, HTML5 / CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Git, Scrum

# Marketing sector client from USA - Endava

Developing and maintaining product for national and federal advertising 6 months as a Java developer, 9 months as an Angular developer

- Javascript
- Typescript
- npm
- Angular 8+
- Angular Material
- Java 8,11,14
- Spring, Spring Boot
- Hibernate
- Postgres
- Java Messaging Service

#### IT sector client form Saudi Arabia - Musala Soft

Developing chat assistant (chat bot) from scratch for support of the client's company 10 months

- Developing chat assistant (chat bot) from scratch for support of the client's company
- Project started from scratch and finished completely in 10 months
- Technologies: Java 8, Spring Boot, Mongo DB, IBM Watson Assistant, IBM Watson Discovery

## State sector client from Bulgaria - Musala Soft

System for national traffic police of R. Bulgaria 7 months

- Integrated system for issuing and processing of driver's traffic penalties, process of issuing driver licenses, generating various reports depending on data stored, issuing documents, automatic jobs for sending tickets to courts aso...
- Developing new features and maintenance
- Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Hibernate, Informix Db, Weblogic Server

Internal Project of One Inside intended to be used in Switzerland – One Inside Hybrid mobile application for users and web page for administration for Swiss camival 3 months

- Developing new features
- Mainly working on the web page for administration
- Fixing bugs
- NodeJs, MongoDb, Git

EUľo*pass* Curriculum Vitae Nikola Furnadjiski

# Projects

## Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Switzerland – One Inside

Web site for Federal Department of Foreign Affairs of Switzerland 4 months

- · Bug fixing for next release
- Technologies: Java, AEM, Git

## Banking sector client from South Africa - One Inside

Single page application, Transactional banking, Personal financial management 15 months

- Project based on AngularJS
- Developing AEM components
- Bug Fixing
- Technologies: JavaScript, AngularJS, AEM, Git

#### **CONFERENCES**

Attended "Java2Days - 2017" international conference for java developers held in Sofia, Bulgaria

## HONOURS AND AWARDS

- Silver and Bronze medal on Macedonian Informatics Olympiad for high school students.
- Numerous first and second awards on regional and national algorithmic informatics competitions for high school students
- First place on "Kangaroo" international mathematics competition.
- 2 times (2010, 2011) bronze medal on "InfoMatrix" international IT competition held in Bucharest, Romania

#### **CERTIFICATONS**

- Angular The Complete Guide (2020 Edition) Certificate issued by Udemy for attending and finished online course lasting 34 hours, August 2020
- OCP (Oracle Certified Professional) for JAVA SE 8 certificate for Java developers issued by Oracle, May 2019
- OCA (Oracle Certified Associate) for JAVA SE 8 certificate for Java developers issued by Oracle, December 2018
- Certificate of Angular 2 issued by Semos Education, April 2017
  - \* these certifications can be seen on my LinkedIn profile in the certificates section

<sup>\*</sup> all these awards can be seen on my LinkedIn profile in the education part attached as media files